Guide to the Joseph Brodsky Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, circa 1959-2000; Series II; 33.99; (86 boxes)
  - Poetry
    - Individual Poems
      - Kolybel'naia ("Rodila tebia v pustyne")
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts and printed version, 1993 (Box 60, Folder 1231)
      - Kolybel'naia ("Zimnii vecher lampu zhzhet"), drafts, undated (Box 60, Folder 1232-1233)
      - Kolybel'naia treskovogo mysa
        - Russian language version, drafts and printed version, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 1234)
        - English interlinear translation by Jim Rice, 1977 (Box 60, Folder 1235)
        - English internlinear by Steven White, undated (Box 60, Folder 1236)
        - English translation by Anthony Hecht, draft, 1978-1979 (Box 60, Folder 1237)
          Includes letters from Hecht to Nancy Meiselas and to Brodsky.
        - English translation by Alan Myers, draft, 1979 (Box 60, Folder 1238)
        - English translation by unidentified translator, draft, undated (Box 60, Folder 1239)
      - "Konchitsia leto. Nachnetsia sentiabr'. Razreshat otstrel," English translation by Brodsky, drafts, proof and printed version, 1987-1992 (Box 60, Folder 1240)
      - Konets prikrasnoi epokhi
        - Russian language version, drafts, 1969 (Box 60, Folder 1241-1242)
          See also: Series I, Correspondence -- General Correspondence -- Etkind, Efim
        - English translation by David Rigsbee, drafts and printed version, undated (Box 60, Folder 1243)
          Includes notes by Barry Rubin.
      - Korneliiu Dolabelle, drafts, [1995] (Box 60, Folder 1244-1245)
      - "Krasavitsa v tiazhelom krasnom plat'e," draft, undated (Box 60, Folder 1246)
      - "Kto ty takoi i kakikh krovei," drafts, undated (Box 60, Folder 1247)
      - Kurs aktsii, draft, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 1248)
      - "Kvadrat priiatnei, chem krug," draft, undated (Box 60, Folder 1249)
      - Kvintet
        - Russian language version, draft, 1978 (Box 60, Folder 1250-1251)
        - English translation by Brodsky, draft, proof and printed version, 1983-1984 (Box 60, Folder 1252)
      - Lagoon
        See:Laguna
      - Laguna
        - Russian language version, draft, [1973] (Box 60, Folder 1253)
        - English translation by Anthony Hecht, draft and printed version, undated (Box 60, Folder 1254)
        - English translation by Masha Vorobiov, drafts, undated (Box 60, Folder 1255)
        - English translation by Daniel Weissbort, printed version, undated (Box 60, Folder 1256)
      - Landsver-Kanal, Berlin, draft, [1989] (Box 60, Folder 1257)
      - Lesnaia idilliia, drafts, 1960s, 1980-1981 (Box 60, Folder 1258)
      - "Let us praise a Southern dandy" (occasional to Andrew Q. Blane), draft, 1989 (Box 60, Folder 1259)
      - Letnaia muzyka, drafts, undated (Box 60, Folder 1260)
        See also: Series I, Correspondence -- General Correspondence -- Tomashevskaia, Anastasia
      - Letter to an archaeologist, drafts and printed version, 1985 (Box 60, Folder 1261)
      - Letter to the Academy
        See: Pis'mo v akademiiu
      - Letters from the Ming Dynasty
        See: Pis'ma Dinastii Min'
      - Lido
        - Russian version, drafts, [1991] (Box 60, Folder 1262-1263)
        - English translation by Brodsky, draft, undated (Box 60, Folder 1264)
        - English translations by Alan Myers, draft, proof and printed version, 1993 (Box 60, Folder 1265)
      - "Life is rough" (occasional to Roger W. Straus), draft, 1996 (Box 60, Folder 1266)
      - "Like woman's head on a clear windy day"
        See: Gorenie
      - Lili Marleen, [by Hans Leip?], Russian translation by Brodsky, drafts, 1996, undated (Box 60, Folder 1267-1268)
        Includes a letter from Bengt Jangfeldt to Ann Kjellberg.
      - Lines for the winter recess, drafts, proof and printed version, 1992 (Box 60, Folder 1269)
      - Lithuanian divertissement
        See: Litovskii divertisment
      - Lithuanian nocturne, drafts and printed version
        See: Litovskii Noktiurn
      - Litovskii divertisment
        - Russian language version, draft, 1971 (Box 60, Folder 1270)
        - English translation by Alan Myers, draft and printed version, 1978 (Box 60, Folder 1271)
        - German translation by unidentified translator, draft, undated (Box 60, Folder 1272)
      - Litovskii noktiurn
        - Russian language version, printed version, 1984 (Box 60, Folder 1273)
        - English translation by Brodsky, draft and printed version, 1987 (Box 60, Folder 1274)
        - English translation by Lyn Coffin and Sergei Shishkoff, printed version, 1986 (Box 60, Folder 1275)
      - "Liubeznyi Tomik, dannyi Tomik" (occasional to [Tomas Venclova]), draft, 1977 (Box 61, Folder 1276)
      - Liubov'
        - Russian language version, draft, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 1277)
        - English translation by John Updike, draft and printed version, undated (Box 61, Folder 1278)
          Includes a letter from John Updike to Carl Proffer.
        - English translations by unidentified translators, two versions, drafts, undated (Box 61, Folder 1279)
      - "Liubov' k Chertkovu Leonidu" (occasional to Leonid Chertkov), draft, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 1280)
        Photocopy. From G. Nikol'skaia.
        Includes a photocopy of notes written by Brodsky on an audio disc of Dylan Thomas reading poetry.
      - Love
        See: Liubov'
      - Love song, draft and printed version, 1996 (Box 61, Folder 1281)
      - Lullaby
        See: Kolybel'naia ("Rodila tebia v pustine")
      - Marcello coat of arms (occasional to Girolamo Marcello), drafts, undated (Box 61, Folder 1282)
      - A martial law carol
        - English language version, proof and printed version, 1983 (Box 61, Folder 1283)
        - French translation by Jean-Marc [Dorizou?], draft, 1991
      - May 24, 1980
        See: "Ia vkhodil vmesto dikogo zveria v kletku"
      - MCMXCIV, English translation by Brodsky, drafts, proof and printed version, 1994-1995 (Box 61, Folder 1284)
      - MCMXCV, English translation by Brodsky, drafts and printed version, 1995, undated (Box 61, Folder 1285)
      - Medea, by Euripides, Russian translation by Brodsky, drafts, proof and printed version, 1994, undated (Box 61, Folder 1286-1287)
      - "Meet Robert Benjamin Silvers" (occasional to Robert Silvers), draft, undated (Box 61, Folder 1288)
      - "Meet Roger W. Straus," copy of a holograph draft produced in New York magazine, 1987 (Box 61, Folder 1289)
      - Meksikanskii divertisment
        - Russian language version, draft, undated (Box 61, Folder 1290)
        - English interlinear translation by Anne Frydman, drafts, undated (Box 61, Folder 1291)
        - English translation by Alan Myers and Brodsky, draft, proof and printed version, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 1292)
        - English translation by Sam Ramer, draft, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 1293)
          Includes a letter from Ramer to Brodsky.
      - "Menia uprekali vo vsem, okromia pogody"
        - Russian language version, [1994] (Box 61, Folder 1294)
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts, proof and printed version, 1994-1996 (Box 61, Folder 1295)
      - Metel' v Massachusetse, drafts, 1990 (Box 61, Folder 1296-1297)
      - Mexican Divertimento
        See: Meksikanskii divertisment
      - Mezhplanetnoe, draft, undated (Box 61, Folder 1298)
      - Mikhailu Baryshnikovu
        - Russian language version, drafts, 1992-1993 (Box 61, Folder 1299-1300)
        - English interlinear translation by Anne Frydman, draft, undated (Box 61, Folder 1301)
        - English translation by Alan Myers, draft, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 1302)
        - English translation by Leslie Simon, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 1303)
          Includes a letter from Simon to Brodsky.
      - Minefield revisited
        See: "Ty, gitaroobraznaia veshch' so sputannoi pautinoi"
      - "Mir sozdan byl iz smeshen'ia griazi, vody, ognia"
        - Russian language version, drafts, [1990] (Box 61, Folder 1304)
        - English translation by Jonathan Aaron and Brodsky, drafts and printed version, 1990-1995 (Box 61, Folder 1305-1307)
          Includes a draft of "When Ed and Jill" (occasional to Ed and Jill Kline) on verso of one draft.
      - "Mne ne tam khorosho, gde ia est'," by Regina Derieva, draft, undated (Box 61, Folder 1308)
      - Monument
        - English translation by W.S. Merwin with Olga Carlisle, printed version, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 1309)
        - French translation by Pierre Forgues, printed version, undated (Box 61, Folder 1310)
          Includes a printed version of an unidentified poem, French translation by Pierre Forgues (titled in French Les Tombereaux ).
      - Monument to the leader, draft
      - Mukha
        - Russian language version, drafts, [1985] (Box 61, Folder 1311-1312)
        - English translation by Jane Miller and Brodsky, drafts and proof, 1987-1988 (Box 61, Folder 1313-1314)
          Includes a letter from Miller to Ann Kjellberg.
      - "My byli za rubezhom," draft, undated (Box 61, Folder 1315)
      - "My ne p'em vina na kraiu derevni"
      - "My zhili v gorode tsveta okamenevshei vodki"
        - Russian language version, drafts, [1994] (Box 61, Folder 1316)
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts and printed version, 1994 (Box 61, Folder 1317)
      - "Mysl' o tebe udaliaetsia, kak razzhalovannaia prisluga"
        - Russian language version, drafts, [1987] (Box 61, Folder 1318-1319)
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts, 1987 (Box 61, Folder 1320)
      - Na nizavisimost' Ukrainy, drafts, 1992 (Box 61, Folder 1321-1322)
      - Na smert' druga
        - Russian language version, draft, 1973 (Box 61, Folder 1323)
        - English interlinear translation by Masha Vorobiov, drafts, undated (Box 61, Folder 1324)
        - English translation by Brodsky, proof and printed version, 1985-1987 (Box 61, Folder 1325)
        - English translation by David McDuff, draft, undated (Box 61, Folder 1326)
        - English translation by Paul Zweig, draft, undated (Box 61, Folder 1327)
      - Na smert' T.S. Eliota, drafts and printed version, 1965, undated (Box 61, Folder 1328-1330)
      - Na smert' Zhukova
        - Russian language version, printed version, undated (Box 61, Folder 1331)
        - English translation by George Kline, drafts, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 1332)
          Includes a letter from Brodsky to Kline.
        - Serbian translation by Miroslav Tokhol', printed version, undated (Box 61, Folder 1333)
      - Na stoletie Anny Akhmatovoi
        - Russian language version, drafts and printed version, 1989, undated (Box 61, Folder 1334-1336)
        - English translation by Frances Laird, draft, 1995 (Box 61, Folder 1337)
        - English interlinear translation by unidentified translator, draft
          See: "Dorogaia, ia vyshel segodnia iz domu pozdno vecherom"
      - "Na Rozovom Kholme"
        See: On Primrose Hill
      - Na Via Dzhulia, draft, [1987] (Box 61, Folder 1338)
      - Na Via Funari
        - Russian language version, drafts, 1995 (Box 61, Folder 1339-1340)
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts and proof and printed version, 1995-1996 (Box 61, Folder 1341-1342)
      - Na vozvrashchenie vesny, draft, undated (Box 62, Folder 1343)
      - Na vystavke Karla Veilinka
        - Russian language version, [1984] (Box 62, Folder 1344-1345)
        - English translation by unidentified translator, draft, undated (Box 62, Folder 1346)
        - Dutch translation by Kees Verheul
          See: Series XI, Papers of Others -- Others -- Kees Verheul Papers
      - Nabrosok, draft, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 1347)
      - Nad vostochnoi rekoi, draft, [1974] (Box 62, Folder 1348)
      - "Nadezhda Filippovna milaia," draft, undated (Box 62, Folder 1349)
      - Nadpis' na knige, drafts, [1991] (Box 62, Folder 1350-1351)
        Includes a draft of Angel.
      - "Nariadu s otopleniem v kazhdom dome," drafts, [1992] (Box 62, Folder 1352-1353)
      - "Nastik, tut moroz" (occasional to Anastasia Tomashevskaia)
      - Nativity
        See: "Nevazhno, chto bylo vokrug, i nevazhno"
      - Natiurmort
        - Russian language version, drafts and printed version, 1971, undated (Box 62, Folder 1354-1355)
        - English translation by Brodsky, draft, undated (Box 62, Folder 1356)
        - English translation by George Kline, printed version, undated (Box 62, Folder 1357)
        - Dutch translation by Kees Verheul
      - Nazidanie, English translation by George Kline and Brodsky, drafts and proofs, 1986-2000, undated (Box 62, Folder 1358-1360)
        Includes letters from Kline to Ann Kjellberg and to Brodsky.
      - "Ne vykhodi iz komnaty, ne sovershai oshibku," draft, undated (Box 62, Folder 1361)
      - Near Alexandria
        See: V okrestnostiakh Aleksandrii
      - "Nemyslimyi kak itog khod'by," drafts, undated (Box 62, Folder 1362)
      - Neofitsial'naia oda na den' rozhdeniia Professora E. G. Etkinda (occasional to Efim Etkind), draft, 1972
        From Iakov Gordin.
      - "Nevazhno, chto bylo vokrug, i nevazhno"
        - Russian language version, draft and printed version, 1996, undated (Box 62, Folder 1363-1364)
        - English translation by Ann Kjellberg and Brodsky, drafts and printed version, 1990, undated (Box 62, Folder 1365)
      - The new Jules Verne
        See:Novyi Zhiul' Vern
      - New life
        See: Novaia zhizn'
      - The New York lullaby, drafts, undated (Box 62, Folder 1366)
      - "Ni toski, ni liubvi, ni pechali," draft, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 1367)
      - Nimfa, oplakivaiushchaia smert' svoego favna (The nymph complaining for the death of her fawn), by Andrew Marvell, Russian translation by Brodsky, drafts, undated (Box 62, Folder 1368)
      - Nizhe -- malen'koe ("Predlagaiu vam malen'koe esse")
        See: Iskiia v oktiabre
      - Nochnoi polet
        - Russian language version, draft, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 1369)
        - Serbian translation by Draginia Ramadanski, printed version, undated (Box 62, Folder 1370)
      - North Baltic
        See: Allenby Road
      - "North is South, and another couple," draft and printed version, 1973 or 1974, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 1371)
      - North Kensington
      - North of Delphi
        See: Primechaniia paporotnika
      - Novaia Angliia, drafts, [1993] (Box 62, Folder 1372-1373)
      - Novaia zhizn'
        - Russian language version, drafts and printed version, undated (Box 62, Folder 1374)
          Includes a printed version of Rozhdestvenskaia zvezda.
        - English translation by David MacFadyen and Brodsky, drafts, proofs and printed version, 1992-1993 (Box 62, Folder 1375-1376)
          Includes correspondence between The New Yorker magazine and Ann Kjellberg.
        - English translation by unidentified translator, draft, undated (Box 62, Folder 1377)
        - Swedish translation by Bengt Jangfeldt, printed version, 1988 (Box 62, Folder 1378)
      - Novye stansy k Avguste
        - Russian language version, draft, 1964 (Box 62, Folder 1379)
        - English translation by unidentified translator, draft, undated (Box 62, Folder 1380)
      - Novyi Zhiul' Vern
        - Russian language version, drafts and printed version, [1976]-1977 (Box 62, Folder 1381-1382)
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts and proof, 1987 (Box 62, Folder 1383-1384)
          Includes a proof of David Montenegro's 1987 interview with Brodsky.
      - "Now that I have a minute," draft, undated (Box 62, Folder 1385)
      - Nunc Dimittis
      - The nymph complaining for the death of her fawn, by Andrew Marvell, Russian translation by Brodsky
        See: Nimfa, oplakivaiushchaia smert' svoego favna
      - "O esli by ptitsi peli i oblaka skuchali"
        - Russian language version, drafts, [1994] (Box 62, Folder 1386)
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts, proof and printed version, 1995-1996 (Box 62, Folder 1387-1388)
      - Oblaka
        - Russian language version, drafts, [1989]
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts, proofs and printed version, 1989-1995 (Box 62, Folder 1389)
      - October tune
        See: Oktiabr'skaia pesnia
      - Oda vesne, draft, undated (Box 62, Folder 1390)
      - Ode to concrete, drafts and printed version, 1995-1996 (Box 62, Folder 1391)
        One draft includes "I applaud your humble -- to be exact" on the verso.
      - Odissei Telemaku
        - Russian language version, drafts and printed version, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 1392-1393)
          Includes a draft of Sreten'e.
        - English translation by Carl Proffer, printed version, undated (Box 62, Folder 1394)
        - English translation by George Kline, printed version, undated
          Includes an excerpt from Gorbunov i Gorchakov, English translation by George Kline.
        - English translation by Harry Thomas
          See: Series I, Correspondence -- General Correspondence -- Thomas, Harry
        - French translation by R. J. MacIntosh, draft, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 1395)
        - Spanish translation by Edmundo García-Girón, draft, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 1396)
          Includes a letter from García-Girón to Brodsky.
      - Odnoi poetesse, drafts, [1965] (Box 62, Folder 1397)
      - Odnomu tiranu
        - Russian language version, draft and printed version, undated (Box 63, Folder 1398)
        - English translation by Alan Myers, draft and printed versions, 1978 (Box 63, Folder 1399)
          Printed versions include selections from V Anglii.
        - English translatoin by Carl Proffer, printed version, undated (Box 63, Folder 1400)
        - English translation by unidentified translator, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1401)
        - Serbian translation by Milovan Danojlić, printed version, 1984 (Box 63, Folder 1402)
      - Odysseus to Telemachus
        See: Odissei Telemaku
      - "Ogon', ty slyshish', nachal ygasat'," draft, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 1403)
      - Oktiabr'skaia pesnia
        - Russian language version, drafts, 1976 (Box 63, Folder 1404-1405)
          One draft includes a letter from Masha Vorobiov to Nancy Meiselas.
        - English interlinear translation by unidentified translator, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1406)
        - English translation by Brodsky, draft and printed version, 1987 (Box 63, Folder 1407)
      - On love
        See: Love
      - On Primrose Hill, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1408)
      - On the death of a friend
        See: Na smert' druga
      - On the death of Zhukov
        See: Na smert' Zhukova
      - "On znal, chto eta bol' v pleche," draft, 1964 or 1965 (Box 63, Folder 1409)
      - "Ona nadevaet chulki, i nastupaet osen'," drafts, 1993 (Box 63, Folder 1410)
      - Once more by the Potomac, draft, proof and printed version, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 1411)
      - Orfei i Artemida
        - Russian language version
        - English translation by unidentified translator, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1412)
      - Orpheus and Artemis
        See: Orfei i Artemida
      - "Osen' -- khoroshee vremia goda, esli vy ne botanik," draft, [1995] (Box 63, Folder 1413-1414)
      - Osen' v Norenskoi
        - Russian language version, drafts, circa 1965, undated (Box 63, Folder 1415)
        - English translation by Brodsky and Daniel Weissbort, drafts, undated (Box 63, Folder 1416)
      - "Osen' vygoniaet menia iz parka," draft, [1970-1971] (Box 63, Folder 1417)
      - Osennii krik iastreba, draft
        See also: "Ia vkhodil vmesto dikogo zveria v kletku"
        - Russian language version, draft, [1971] (Box 63, Folder 1418)
        - English translation by Alan Myers and Brodsky, drafts and printed version, 1975-1987 (Box 63, Folder 1419)
      - "Osennii vecher v skromnom gorodke"
        - Russian language version, draft, [1972] (Box 63, Folder 1420)
        - English translation by George Kline, draft and proof, 1973 (Box 63, Folder 1421-1422)
      - "Osen'iu iz gnezda," draft, 1964 (Box 63, Folder 1423)
      - Ostanovka v pustyne
        - Russian language version, draft and printed version, 1966, undated (Box 63, Folder 1424-1425)
        - English translation by George Kline, printed version, undated (Box 63, Folder 1426)
        - Polish translation by Wiktor Woroszylski, 1987
      - Ostrov Prochida, drafts, 1994 (Box 63, Folder 1427)
      - Otkrytka iz Bukhary, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1428)
      - Otkrytka iz goroda K., draft
        See: S vidom na more and Ramunas and Elmira Katilius family archive
      - Otkrytka Metsenatu, by Jerzy Harasymowicz, Russian translation by Brodsky
        See: V Krakove, by Jerzy Harasymowicz
      - Otryvok ("Eto bylo plavan'e skvoz' tuman"), draft, [1969-1970] (Box 63, Folder 1429)
        Includes a draft of "Osen' vygoniaet menia iz parka."
      - Otryvok ("Na vas ne podnimaetsia ruka"), draft, 1962 (Box 63, Folder 1430)
      - Otryvok ("V ganzeiskoi gostinitse "Iakor""), draft, [1964] (Box 63, Folder 1431)
        Found in Brodsky's desk in South Hadley.
      - Otvet na anketu, drafts, [1993] (Box 63, Folder 1432-1433)
      - "Oysters, like girls, like pearls," draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1434)
      - Pamiati Klifforda Brauna
        - Russian language version, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1435)
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts, proof and printed version, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 1436-1438)
      - Pamiati N.N., draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1439)
      - Pamiati Ottsa: Avstraliia
        - Russian language version, draft, [1989] (Box 63, Folder 1440)
        - English translation by Brodsky, draft, proof and printed version, 1989-1990 (Box 63, Folder 1441)
        - English translation by Carol Rumens, draft, 1990 (Box 63, Folder 1442)
      - Pamiati Professora Braudo, draft
        See:Series XI, Papers of Others -- Others -- Ramunas and Elmira Katilius family archive
      - Pamiati T. B.
        - English translation by Paul Zweig, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1443)
        - English translation by unidentified translator, printed version, undated (Box 63, Folder 1444)
      - Pamiati V.B. Eitsa (In memory of W.B. Yeats), by W.H. Auden, Russian translation by Brodsky, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1445)
      - Pamiatnik Garibal'di, Vashinton skver, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1446)
      - A part of speech
      - Pastoral', drafts, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 1447-1448)
      - Pateticheskaia gondola (Sorgegondolen), by Tomas Tranströmer
        - English interlinear translation by unidentified translator, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1449)
          Series I, Correspondence -- General Correspondence -- Transtromer, Tomas
        - Russian translation by Brodsky, draft, 1989? (Box 63, Folder 1450)
      - "Pchely ne uleteli, vsadnik ne uskakal. V kofeine"
        - Russian language version, draft, undated (Box 63, Folder 1451)
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts, proof and printed version, 1988-1993 (Box 63, Folder 1452)
      - Peizazh s navodneniem
        - Russian language version, draft, 1993 (Box 63, Folder 1453)
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts and proofs, 1993 (Box 63, Folder 1454)
        - German translation by Jörg Trobitius, printed version, undated (Box 63, Folder 1455)
      - Pen'e bez muzyki
        - Russian language version, draft and printed version, 1969-1971 (Box 63, Folder 1456-1457)
        - English translation by David Rigsbee, draft and printed version, 1975 (Box 63, Folder 1458-1459)
      - Pered pamiatnikom A. S. Pushkinu v Odesse, drafts, [1969] or [1970] (Box 63, Folder 1460)
      - "Perhaps this show is done in vain," draft, 1976 (Box 63, Folder 1461)
      - Persian arrow
        See: Persidskaia strela
      - Persidskaia strela
        - Russian language version, draft, [1993] (Box 63, Folder 1462)
        - English translation by Brodsky, drafts and proof, 1994 (Box 63, Folder 1463)